# **Matthew Young**

Foster City, California y.matt12@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/matthew-young-07 matthewyoung777.gitlab.io/portfolio/

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software engineer intern with experience coding in Python, JavaScript, and Java building back-end systems in Node.js, Django, databases such as PostgreSQL, MongoDB, as well as user interfaces on the web with React.js and mobile app interfaces with React Native.

#### **SKILLS**

Technical Skills: JavaScript, Python, Django, Fast API, Docker, React.js, React Native Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Git, Gitlab, Heroku

Industry Knowledge: Agile Methodologies, Software Engineering, Algorithms, Unit Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Analysis, Data Science Interpersonal Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Problem solving, Adaptability, Quick Learning, Leadership

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer Intern**

#### Networky.ai

October 2023 - Present, Palo Alto, CA

- · Engineered a highly responsive and user-friendly mobile site, optimizing it for on-the-go networking to enhance user experience.
- · Documented the development process, architecture, code structure, and deployment procedures, for future reference and knowledge sharing.
- · Generated AI Chatbot training data transcribing video speech to text, web crawling, and cleaning datasets to be optimizing as training data set.
- · Proactively identified and communicated bug test reports, contributing to the overall improvement of the application's reliability and performance.

# **Founding Engineer**

**Forge Fitness** 

September 2023 - Present, San Francisco

- · Leading a small team designing and developing a mobile-first Fitness accountability app helping people reach their fitness goals.
- · Conducted competitive analysis of market leading alternatives to drive feature selection and product differentiation.
- · Implemented dynamic mobile UI to improve user signup flow using React Native.
- · Designed data model architecture for a MongoDB database for improved API response times up to 100ms.
- · Implemented a RESTful API using Node.js to extract and update data in a MongoDB database.

### **Autonomous Vehicle Test Specialist**

Cruise

July 2021 - July 2022, San Francisco, CA

- $\cdot$  Increased drivable testing zones by 50% through lane and route mapping techniques.
- · Pinpointed and communicated problematic drive behavior data with engineers to reduce driving error frequency by 30%.
- · Trained fleet operators introducing new techniques for vehicle testing which increased driverless mileage accumulation by 100%.

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Paper Stonks**

 $Hack reactor \cdot https://gitlab.com/apex-legends1/paper-stonks \cdot October \ 2022 - December \ 2022 - De$ 

- · Developed a web-based mock stock trading application simulating investment portfolios and stock trading using real-time stock price data.
- · Orchestrated the creation of a highly scalable and secure REST API powered by Fast API to facilitate seamless data access.
- · Crafted engaging and interactive user interfaces using React.js, integrated with real-time stock data visualization through Chart.js.
- $\cdot \ Spearheaded \ the \ implementation \ of \ Docker-based \ microservice \ architectures \ for \ efficient \ deployment \ and \ scalability.$
- · Developed GitLab CI/CD automation pipeline while leading a 5-member team to meet project goals.

#### Car Car

Hackreactor · https://gitlab.com/matthewyoung777/project-beta · September 2022 - October 2022

- $\cdot \ \, \text{Engineered a web app streamlining interactions between a dealership and its clientele, inventory tracking, vehicle sales, service appointments.}$
- $\cdot \text{ Crafted a dynamic and user-friendly front-end UI with React.} js, focusing on the appointment microservice for enhanced user engagement.}$
- $\cdot \ \text{Implemented a robust RESTful API for seamless data access within the appointment microservice with Django.}$
- · Held Scrum of scrums for discussing daily progress and sprint goals amongst the team, collaborating with Git version control.
- · Designed and executed a scalable data model and microservices structure, with Django and Docker for performance and deployment efficiency.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Software Engineering**

Hack Reactor · San Francisco, CA · November 2022

# Bachelor of Arts - BA, Economics

University of Washington  $\cdot$  Seattle, WA  $\cdot$  2019

· Dean's List recognition for 7 quarters